# **Austin Schroeder**

(515) 490-8804 || <u>austinsoundy@gmail.com</u> || <u>LinkedIn</u> || <u>Github</u> || <u>Portfolio</u> San Diego, CA

# Introduction

I'm a Software Developer, currently designing and building modern web apps with slick, responsive UIs. I'm obsessed with learning and growing professionally as well as personally.

A long time ago, in a galaxy far far away... I organized multiple aspects of large scale live concerts, tours, and events - specializing in audio engineering. I've since decided to take all those skills/experience and make a career change, in hopes of keeping my suitcase unpacked.

# **Technical Skills**

**Front-End** | JavaScript, React, Typescript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Googling, Adobe Photoshop **Back-End** | Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Firebase, RESTful API design, User Auth

# Experience

# **Coding Projects**

SASS Portfolio Repository | Deployed

Tech Stack: HTML, SASS/CSS, JavaScript, Adobe Photoshop

A responsive multi page mock 'tech' portfolio site. Created to learn SASS and try out some humor in my work.

- Used Photoshop to edit custom images
- Completed over the course of 2 days
- No build system. Raw HTML, JS

#### React/TS Trivia Game Repository | Deployed

Tech Stack: React w/ Typescript, Styled Components

A simple trivia game using Open Trivia DB API and scorekeeping feature

- Experimented with creative with new CSS techniques
- Attention to async/await and speed of API calls
- Easily customizable to change question category or difficulty

#### Audio Analyzer Repository | Deployed

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Canvas, vanilla JavaScript, Parcel bundler

Real Time Analyzer (RTA) web app that will provide a visual display of audio data being collected via device mic.

- RGB to HSL conversion to provide coloration for amplitude of specific frequency data
- No libraries or frameworks used
- Will make everybody else in your office wonder what the heck you are doing...

#### Eventric - Front-End Developer: April 2022-current

Eventric is the leading SaaS developer of live event and tour management software solutions. We power efficiency and measurable bottom-line profitability for event production and tour management. We've designed and cultivated our web, mobile, and cloud solutions Master Tour and Live Access to precisely benefit the needs of the top professionals across music, tv/film, sports, production, corporate, and touring industries.

- Stack includes: React, Electron, Redux, React-Native, React w/ Typescript, React Context, Styled Components, Mocha and Cypress Unit testing
- Agile Scrum workflow with daily standups, sprints, and PR review
- Reformatted a lot of legacy React code to more modern functional components with hooks
- Upkeep of user feedback and feature requests, as well as bug fixes

#### Cont.

#### Ace Relocation - Front-End Developer: Jan 2022-April 2022

Managing the end-to-end life cycle for the production of software and applications. Overseeing and guiding the analyzing, writing, building, and deployment of software. Overseeing the automated testing and providing feedback to management during the development process.

- Integration of VueJS, ReactJS and NodeJS applications into other 3rd party APIs and systems
- Created <u>Ace Customer Portal</u> Ex. Order Number: AHU192580 Email: CHAHAL408@GMAIL.COM
- Design and implementation of low-latency, high-availability, and performant web applications
- Integration of data storage solutions (SQL Server, Azure Blob Storage)

# Knowcap - Contract Full Stack Software Engineer: Nov 2021-Jan 2022

Utilizing MERN stack to develop an API that allows companies to agree to pay a service provider based on revenue for a period of time.

- Responsible for implementing Plaid API to add user bank accounts, calculate revenue percentage, find income/revenue.
- Use GitHub Actions as the basis for CI/CD pipeline with GCP
- Implement OpenAPI v3.0.+ for the backend API to service the frontend.
- Use JSON Web Tokens for session authorization
- Implement test driven development using Jest library for API backend
- React Bootstrap is used for components

### Live Concert Production-Independent Contractor: 2011 - 2021

Positions include: Production Manager, Tour Manager, Audio Engineer

- Acts include: Backstreet Boys, Rage Against the Machine, Usher, John Fogerty, Foo Fighters, + many more.
- Created many systems of in-depth efficiency for planning and executing production and travel logistics.
- Planned and maintained budgets of up to \$1,000,000.
- Often required to learn complex digital audio systems and device networking with little time and limited resources
- Managed teams of up to 30, and created enjoyable work environments to keep high morale

# Sound Image, San Diego, CA - Contract Global Account Manager: 2018-2021

- Coordinated and negotiated audio equipment for worldwide arena concert tours.
- Built and maintained client relationships via daily communications and networking events
- Brought in an annual average of \$500k+ in sales with budget management

# ECS Jets, Los Angeles, CA - Aviation Advisor/Sales: 2019-2020

Coordinated aircraft operators with international hubs on logistics and sourcing aircraft

#### Education

# **General Assembly- Remote: 2021**

# "Full-Stack MERN, Python, & Django Engineering

- ❖ 650+ hours of full-stack immersive web development with a challenging 12 week curriculum.
- ❖ Developed projects using pair programming with focus on full-stack web apps, debugging, and collab using git version control.

# Full Sail University- Orlando, FL - BA Entertainment Business and Recording Engineering: 2005-2007

- Perfect attendance award
- ❖ 1st place in university-wide mixing competition